<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-05-13T22:53:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Limiting repetitive markup with middleman</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/05/14/Limiting-repetition-in-your-html/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/05/14/Limiting-repetition-in-your-html/</id>
    <published>2015-05-13T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-07T17:46:49-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While working on a section of an internal project there was something that was bothering me about the way that I structured everything with static pages. Essentially the section contained an index page which linked to four individual view/team pages. Pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="diagram_1" src="/images/blog/yaml/diagram_1-5b08514e.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team pages were structured the same but contained content particular to that team such as its own about content, members, and leader info. The best part about this monster I created was that it would breed like bunnies…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="baby_bunnies" src="/images/blog/yaml/baby_bunnies-6bb5f703.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more team pages were added that same html markup would have to be copied. Even more fun – adding and updating content would not be pretty and I could create more enemies than Joffrey from the Game of Thrones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to leave the darkside and find a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="one-view-to-the-rescue"&gt;One view to the rescue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this approach is to solve these problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each team is it’s own “view” = ton’s of repetition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to edit data pertaining to a team you currently have to update it in the index and its individual team page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The static html files are tedious to enter data into&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Create easy to edit data files that feed into one view. It would work like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="diagram_2" src="/images/blog/yaml/diagram_2-47533dc9.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="creating-the-data-files"&gt;Creating the "data files"&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stated before the data for each of the team pages was pretty similar. So having data files that could feed into one view which would generate new team pages made sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to research and use my new friend, YAML aka “YAML Ain't Markup Language" for these data files. What is great about YAML is that it was designed to be easily mapped to data types common to most high-level languages: lists, associative arrays, and scalar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a YAML data file that would feed into the view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/c2e56783fc953ea2c7fd.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data creates generates a giant hash of keys and values like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/115e11b03387de806af8.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like dealing with hashes good for you. I'm a bigger fan of working with objects. Using Ruby you can create methods which turn these key &amp;amp; values into an object like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/967bf1974a2d958b0ca5.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new methods we created can now be used in our view using Embedded Ruby:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/65ce56bee20f12a3b8c6.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id="everything-is-so-much-cleaner"&gt;Everything is so much cleaner!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using tools such as YAML, Ruby, and Embedded Ruby allowed me to clean up the structure of my project. With a singular view for team pages the duplication work that someone would have to do if they were somehow assigned to add 100 new teams is now gone. Imagine manually creating 100 static html pages and then having to apply future changes to each static page…yuck.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CSS Architecture</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/04/24/CSS-Architecture/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/04/24/CSS-Architecture/</id>
    <published>2015-04-23T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-07T16:43:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was first learning to program in Ruby I remember being so excited to have a working program. I was extremely nervous to show my work to my mentor. And as we went through my code she was very patient and told me that she could tell I worked hard on it. It meant so much - and honestly was great fuel to keep me excited about programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the last few months of my student software apprenticeship and I realized just how terrible my code was. I had no regard for clean or structured code - I was a beginner and I needed to know how to make things work above all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see this same pattern in my Design Apprenticeship but perhaps the rules for the design and structure for setting up your project files and CSS is less clear and more opinionated than than it seemed to me when dealing with backend code. It just seems like everyone is trying to find a way to solve CSS architecture - but no one has found a solution to win over the masses quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to start forming my own ideas on CSS architecture my mentor had me research a few of the most popular ways to structure my code and files: OOCSS(Object Oriented CSS), BEM(Block, Element, Modifier), and SMACSS(Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="oocssobject-oriented-css"&gt;OOCSS(Object Oriented CSS)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Object oriented CSS reminds me a lot about of the philosophies I learned during my student software apprenticeship. The idea is the same - while coding it is important to write it in a way that is clean and reusable. The benefits of coding this way are having cleaner, smaller, and more maintainable stylesheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bemblock-element-modifier"&gt;BEM(Block, Element, Modifier)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEM was a really interesting one to research. It’s a bit ugly but it’s purpose is beautiful. It’s ultimately trying to solve the problem of CSS being unreadable and confusing to those who didn’t write it themselves. If we’re honest with ourselves, maybe the classes we wrote ourselves a few weeks ago don’t seem to make sense anymore. This problem was also present when I was learning Ruby —&amp;gt; Write methods that are more descriptive. In reference to CSS —&amp;gt; Write classes that are more descriptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="BEM" src="/images/bem-7e07a280.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="smacssscalable-and-modular-architecture-for-css"&gt;SMACSS(Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SMACSS was a little confusing at first but broken down it is simply trying to find a universal way for everyone to structure their project folders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;style.scss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_base.scss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_layout.scss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_modules.scss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_state.scss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_theme.scss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I think that the state and theme folders are not necessary all the time and I don’t think i’ll be adding them to my file structure. However the other folders will help my organization a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;style.scss
The master file that imports all of your other stylesheets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_base.scss
This is where all the base styles live; resets, element defaults, default font sizes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_layout.scss
In this section you specify all types of layout containers, such as header, footer, content, sidebar, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_modules.scss
Every module should be completely independent of its context and should work within any layout container or other module.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Say No</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/04/21/Say-No/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/04/21/Say-No/</id>
    <published>2015-04-20T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-07T16:43:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago a friend said something to me that I silently found offensive. He stated that I was a “people pleaser”. I couldn’t exactly pinpoint why this stuck with me so much… I mean how is wanting to make people happy a bad quality? If more people went out of their way to make others happy wouldn’t that make the world be a better place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I learned a valuable lesson: Everyone needs to be able to say no. And people pleasing doesn’t always just mean making others happy - it can also mean sacrificing your health &amp;amp; happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short I was asked to take on several tasks - some which should not have been my responsibility. Knowing I had a lot on my plate I still took on more responsibilities than I should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to accomplish all of the tasks but that came with a lot of stress and little sleep. I should have stood my ground and said no. That would have been the professional thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Saying “yes” too much could jeopardize more than just your patience. Taking on more than you’re capable could result in illness or burning out. When you become sick, it’s a struggle to help yourself, much less everyone around you, so cut your losses and say “no” for the sake of your health.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SVG's</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/03/25/SVG's/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/03/25/SVG's/</id>
    <published>2015-03-24T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-07T16:43:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I first started working with images way back when, I would save them as a jpeg (Joint Photographic Experts Group). The problem with saving an image as a jpeg is it has a “lossy” file compression. This means that data is lost as the file is compressed which causes a noticeable loss of quality. When I discovered this, you can imagine how cool I felt when I started saving my images and graphics as png’s (Portable Network Graphics) -  which are “lossless”. A file type that does not lose data so that it can be viewed at a high quality resolution seemed like the end all solution for web images and graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the world of people accessing the internet via various devices, screen sizes, and resolutions as well as the trend of responsive web design. Images and graphics not only need to be displayed at high quality, they need to be scalable and responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been really intrigued with the world of responsive web design which is why I stumbled upon SVG’s (Scalable Vector Graphics). An SVG is a XML-based vector image format for 2D graphics that has support for interactivity and animation. A few benefits of using an SVG are its scalability, and SEO friendliness because is can include descriptions which can be searched by search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my last project: &lt;a title="Self Assessment" href="http://ericagarcia.me/projects/assessment/"&gt;Self Assessment&lt;/a&gt;, I was looking for a way to display my ratings and decided to experiement with SVG graphics and animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="svg_circles" src="/images/blog/svg/svg_circles-3604d17d.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code to create one of these animated circles looks a little confusing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/09fbb1e2d4b5dfc8af2d.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id="lets-break-it-down"&gt;Let's break it down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it would be easier to view this problem as a series of different sections like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="svg_circles" src="/images/blog/svg/svg_circles_divided-99fd748c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code to create a sectioned circle would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/a87b2b0803ed122c9bbd.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id="viewbox-and-g"&gt;viewBox and g&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first things we see listed are svg viewBox and g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/d32a3bf9cfd12eb5279f.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viewBox&lt;/strong&gt; - contains four numbers (min-x, min-y, width and height) which define how the graphics fit in its container element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;g&lt;/strong&gt; - This element is used to group SVG shapes together as a single shape. The advantages of doing this are you can now target grouped shapes and add things such as transformations or styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="paths"&gt;Paths&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create these animated circles several paths were needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/1ba09a94d2c33a8954e4.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think out of everything, paths can look pretty intimidating. But they aren't so bad! To make things a little easier, let's just grab the first path and disect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/99667e908a90482a804c.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;path&lt;/strong&gt; - This element is used to draw advanced shapes combined from lines, arcs, curves etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt; - this is the d attribute which the drawing commands which are given to a “virtual pen”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt; - “Move to” command - This should always be first thing listed in a path! Here the virtual pen is being moved to point 0, -100
  &lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/99667e908a90482a804c.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; - “Arc” command has five parameters. The first two set the radius of the arc, the third sets the rotation of the arc’s -axis compared to the normal x-axis, and the fourth and fifth parameters are the large-arc-flag and the sweep flag. The large-arc flag  determines if the arc that should be drawn should be greater than, or less than 180 degrees, and in the end determines which direction the arc will travel around a given circle. The sweep-flag determines if the arc should begin moving at negative or positive angles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rx(radius in x-direction), ry(radius in y-direction), x-axis rotation, large-arc flag, sweep-flag&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="svg_arcs" src="/images/blog/svg/SVGArcs_Flags-a119f4a6.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the virtual pen is using absolute coordinates - starting at 0, -100 to the point 86.6, -50 ( the last two numbers in the list of A coordinates). The first two numbers of A are the same 100, 100 so this results in a circular arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/99667e908a90482a804c.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Note that an uppercase “A” uses absolute coordinates and a lowercase “a” uses relative coordinates (relative from its start point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="getting-fancy"&gt;Getting Fancy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about that second SVG? This is a piece that is used as a mask for the circle animation. Told you we were getting fancy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/2ed94c52b0eec7222230.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This contains some of the other elements but a couple new ones as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt; (absolute) &lt;strong&gt;c&lt;/strong&gt; (relative) - (x1 y1 x2 y2 x y)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This draws a &lt;a title="Cubic Bézier curve" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B%C3%A9zier_curve#Cubic_B.C3.A9zier_curves"&gt;Cubic Bézier curve&lt;/a&gt; from the current point to (x,y) using (x1,y1) as the control point at the beginning of the curve and (x2, y2) as the control point at the end of the curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Z or z&lt;/strong&gt; are simple guys - they simply close the path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="styling"&gt;Styling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was browsing through a lot of SVG XML code I saw tons of inline styles - which kind of brought me nightmares of when I used to be able to sprint to the mailbox faster than the internet could load an image. When styling, try to place everything in your CSS - some things won't work but your SVG code will look much cleaner without all of its inline styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was just a brief breakdown of some of the many elements available for building SVG's. And perhaps an easier less exploratory route to make a circle would have been simply using the SVG circle element. This element uses the parameters cx, cy, and r where the cx and cy attributes define the x and y coordinates of the center of the circle and the r attribute defines the radius of the circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/260ab17f67ab6965e263.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this excited you, what are you still doing here? You should probably be experimenting with SVG's :)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Visual Hierarchy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/03/18/Visual-Hierarchy/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/03/18/Visual-Hierarchy/</id>
    <published>2015-03-17T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-07T16:43:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visual hierarchy is vital in every design in order to create an enjoyable user experience. Good visual hierarchy is the responsible use of color, contrast, texture, shape, position, orientation, and size to create different levels of relative importance. It’s a difficult task to responsibly use all of these exciting tools to create a cohesive and  enjoyable experience for the user. However, with a better understanding of how our users perceive the information we provide them, we’ll have more guidance as to how to efficiently guide our viewers from one piece of content to the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-do-humans-view-information"&gt;How do humans view information?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1920s German psychologists created theories in order to describe the capability of our brains to generate and organize visual elements into groups or “unified wholes”. This branch of study is called Gestalt psychology and a major part of this study involves the theory of the gestalt effect. The gestalt effect contains a few principles that explain the reasoning behind why our brains are naturally able to categorize information: grouping similar visual elements and organizing them into meaningful patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few principles of the gestalt effect are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Law of Similarity:&lt;/strong&gt; When things are similar, the human brain tends to perceive them as a group or pattern. Therefore, something different from the group will tend to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="similarity_example" src="/images/blog/hierarchy/similarity-2c0ccf74.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Law of Continuation:&lt;/strong&gt; Continuation occurs when the eye is naturally compelled to move through one object to another object. Elements arranged on a line or curve are perceived to be more related than elements not on a line or curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="continuation_example" src="/images/blog/hierarchy/continuation-7d619156.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Law of Closure:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a really cool one. This occurs when the human brain is able to fill in missing information in order to create a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="closure_example" src="/images/blog/hierarchy/closure-692a4c9c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Law of Proximity:&lt;/strong&gt; When elements are placed in close proximity the brain tends to categorize them into a group as where things that are placed further apart from each other are viewed as  separate groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="proximity_example" src="/images/blog/hierarchy/proximity-b12d3d11.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure and Ground Relationships:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the brains ability to create a relationship between the object and its background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="figure_ground_example" src="/images/blog/hierarchy/figure_ground-fe0a9c91.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-does-the-gestalt-theory-help-us"&gt;How does the gestalt theory help us?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big take away from the principles of the gestalt effect theory is that humans see everything in terms of relationships. With this information designers can apply the gestalt principles to basic design principles such as contrast, repetition, alignment, and proximity to communicate better with their users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-is-hierarchy-created"&gt;How is hierarchy created?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hierarchy is created by changing the visual weight of each element. Something with more visual weight is considered higher in the ranks of hierarchy which means that something with less visual weight is less important. Visual weights can be controlled through the use of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contrast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrast is using the difference in visual properties to make things distinguishable from each other. Shifts in color, size, shape, and position can help create a sense of visual hierarchical importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elements that are larger in size carry more visual weight. That being said, the most important elements of your design should be bigger and the least important elements should be smaller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Color&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bold, contrasting colors can call attention to an element and raise its importance in a design. It can also be used as a hierarchy organizational tool in something such as infographic. The value (the darkness and lightness of an element can also give it more or less visual weight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proximity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proximity separates elements from each other and creates sub-hierarchies. Items that are packed closely together create a dense area and therefore create more visual weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repetition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repetition instantly attaches meaning to elements and communicates that elements are at the same level in the hierarchy. An example of this would be a human knowing that something is a link because they are all styled the same throughout the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="pulling-it-all-together"&gt;Pulling it all together&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you are working on a project it is important to know what your goals are. What are you trying to communicate to the viewer? Which information needs to be prioritized? When you have your design, ask yourself whether or not there is a nice visual flow from one piece of content to the next. While drafting, if literally numbering your pieces of content in order of importance helps - go for it! If you’re having trouble, try standing back and viewing your design while squinting in order to see what pops out to you first. Is it the content that you numbered 1? If yes, move on to see if the rest of the numbers follow sequentially. If no, you’ll need to play around with your visual weight tools a little more. And once you’re done creating a visual hierarchy masterpiece be sure to celebrate!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Semantic Elements</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/03/05/HTML5-Semantic-elements/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/03/05/HTML5-Semantic-elements/</id>
    <published>2015-03-04T21:53:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-07T16:43:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first 20 years of my life when someone would tell me that they were interested in learning a new language I would immediately think that they were talking about a foreign language. But in the past year, hanging around people who are passionate about programming and web development, “learning a new language” has a whole new meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps learning a programming or markup language is not so different from learning a foreign language. There are plenty of similarities between learning a language such as Spanish and a markup language such as HTML (HyperText Markup Language).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such example is the study of Semantics: The study of the meanings of words and phrases in a language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In HTML5 there are non-semantic elements as well as semantic elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-semantic:&lt;/strong&gt; These elements do not tell us the meaning of it’s content
&lt;strong&gt;Examples:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semantic:&lt;/strong&gt; These elements give meaning to the content
&lt;strong&gt;Examples:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;,  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering what is means to “give meaning” or to “not give meaning” to content. Semantic elements explicitly label its content and enable computers, search engines, screen readers, etc. to read and understand the content on our web pages. And not only does it help machines better understand our HTML,  it creates a universal language so that when someone else jumps onto your markup they can better understand all of the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few HTML5 Semantic tags explained using a project I worked on this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ericagarcia.me/projects/semantics/"&gt;&lt;img alt="My Semantics Project" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_project-cbbf32a5.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="header-"&gt;&amp;lt; header &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is a structural element that represents a group of introductory or navigational aids. It typically contains a section’s heading, but can hold other content (a search form, relevant logos, etc.) if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be multiple headers in a document but be sure not to overuse this element. For example, if the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element only contains a single heading element its unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="header_example" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_header-06fa3bb7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="footer-"&gt;&amp;lt; footer &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The footer identifies the closing or end of a page, article, section, or other segment of a page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footers may contain things such as short list of links to various pages of a site, social media icons, copyright information, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="footer_example" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_footer-f5e279a7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="nav-"&gt;&amp;lt; nav &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nav identifies a section of major navigational links on a page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This element is also one that is commonly overused. An example of over-usage would be using it for the links located in your footer as they are not considered “major” navigational links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="nav_example" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_nav-50208e2f.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="article-"&gt;&amp;lt; article &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;article&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is used to contribute to the documents structure. It contains a standalone piece of content that may be independently distributed or reused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An easy test to see whether something would make sense as an &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;article&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is:
Would it’s content make sense independent of it’s context? If so, it’s a good candidate for an &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;article&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="article_example" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_article-c0a138b0.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="section-"&gt;&amp;lt; section &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A section is also used to contribute to the documents structure. It is used to group different articles into different purposes or subjects, or to define the different sections of a single article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="section_example" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_section-9d3f336d.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="aside-"&gt;&amp;lt; aside &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aside element holds content, such as sidebars, inserts, or brief explanations that is separate from but related to the content surrounding it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples for an aside could be advertisements, or groups of navigation items. In this case I have a list of speakers which navigate to their personal websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="aside_example" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_aside-6ad45d68.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous project I used a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to label a quote that was pulled from the magazine article and used as a print “pull-quote.” However this was not the right use of a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="blockquote-"&gt;&amp;lt; blockquote &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is used to specify that a section is quoted from another source:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote cite="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091042/quotes"&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Life moves pretty fast. If you don't stop and look around once in a while, you could miss it..&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;— &amp;lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091042/quotes"&amp;gt;Ferris Bueller&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cite is used to specify the source of the quotation*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="q-"&gt;&amp;lt; q &amp;gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;q&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is an inline html quotation element that is used for short quotations that don’t require paragraph breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="blockquote_example" src="/images/blog/semantics/Semantics_blockquote-b9ca6eb1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
