<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-07-23T22:53:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Eric Day 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/24/Pairing-with-Eric-Day-2/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/24/Pairing-with-Eric-Day-2/</id>
    <published>2015-07-23T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-02T23:46:19-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last day of my pairing tour was a busy one! In the morning I worked on more business cards for London and organizing all of the files for our seperate offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch Eric took Nelsol and I through a client project that is looking to improve the user experience and design of their app. As Eric took us through the project I could immediately see things that Nelsol and I could do to make the application more user friendly. I honestly wish that I could design the entire thing from the ground up but that’s not in the cards. I also think this project would benefit greatly by speaking with the users so we could eliminate a lot of the noise and unneeded material within the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going through the app was pretty tiring so Eric and I took a ping pong break to relax before we dove into pairing on SLAM again. After the best, most highly skilled round of ping-pong in the world, Eric and I showed the wireframes we had been working on to the rest of the slammers. They were excited about the proposed features and one thing i’m really glad I did was ask them for ideas that we could add. The guys came up with some really great ideas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all then began drafting out more of our ideas, writing up project stories, and breaking up into pairs to knock out some features. Eric and I continued to work on the wireframes and the others began to work on adding Google Authorization to the App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pairing session was cut short today because I received my “Challenges”.  Challenges are two weeks of work that will determine whether or not I have a future at 8th Light as a designer. They consist of….just kidding. It’s a secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Believe in yourself, take on your challenges, dig deep within yourself to conquer fears. Never let anyone bring you down. You got to keep going. –Chantal Sutherland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Nelsol Day 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/23/Pairing-with-Nelsol-Day-2/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/23/Pairing-with-Nelsol-Day-2/</id>
    <published>2015-07-22T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-02T23:46:19-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was my second day pairing with my mentor, Nelsol. We started off the day working on some print collateral for a client. I’m very comfortable working with the Adobe Creative Suite and print materials so this project was right up my alley. The downer was that we were on a tight deadline so I tried my best to keep composure, remain calm, and have fun regardless of the tight deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our workflow was constantly broken up with client meetings, messages from other project members, and questions from internal members. We worked together to stay on task and once we were comfortable with the print we sent it to the client and the printer to get their feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While awaiting feedback we jumped right into some tickets for one of our clients. We worked through some tough problems because the code base was drowning in dependencies. Trying our best to use our principles and keep the code as clean as possible we completed the tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most helpful things that Nelsol showed me today was his workflow. The man is extremely organized and to be honest with how many things he has to juggle it would be a nightmare if he wasn’t. First, he took me through the process of submitting a ticket to be reviewed before a pull request can be requested. He then showed me the clients tracking system for each feature and how ownership is passed from person to person throughout the process. Because ownership is constantly changing, Nelsol has his own way of tracking his work on various projects. He uses trello.com, a free organization tool for teams and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson of the day: Be Organized!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t say you don’t have enough time.  You have exactly the same number of hours per day that were given to Helen Keller, Pasteur, Michaelangelo, Mother Teresea, Leonardo da Vinci, Thomas Jefferson, and Albert Einstein. – H. Jackson Brown, Jr.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Kevin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/22/Pairing-with-Kevin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/22/Pairing-with-Kevin/</id>
    <published>2015-07-21T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-02T23:46:19-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I took a trip over to Groupon to pair with Kevin on an Ember.js App. It was a cool field trip and Groupon’s office certainly had a lot going on. Most memorable – a giant cardboard kitty in a massive spaceship. I’m pretty sure if I were to go there again there would be a 100 things that I missed the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was nervous to pair on the Ember App because I had planned to go through the Treehouse tutorial the night before but ended up falling asleep with my giant headphones on before I could finish all of the videos. I was more exhausted than I thought! I continued to prepare on the train ride in even though I get motion sick while riding and reading. I guess I was scared that I wouldn’t be able to contribute as much as I had hoped if I didn’t know Ember because I was studying like a college student about to take a final exam. Luckily, Kevin quickly filled me in that he was also just starting with Ember. Feeeeeew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together we started drafting out the function of his and Mike’s app on the whiteboard like I always love to do. We then took those ideas, set up our environment and began setting up the static stage &amp;amp; grid for the app. We also started organizing our folder structure to make sure that our CSS was well organized as we built out the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun to work alongside Kevin to figure out how to implement Ember’s helpers with the styling that we wished to have. We both took turns driving and paid attention to what each person was doing. This helped a great deal as Kevin was able to catch my mistakes and vice versa. It also helped out a great deal when I was developing on the browser and would accidently save and the auto-reloader would run losing all of my changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I had to leave for a client meeting Kevin and I were able to add some basic styling, fonts, explore, edit &amp;amp; add some SVG graphics, and brainstorm additional styles they could add later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how refreshing it was to be able to start a project from scratch again. After working in webs lately, I truly appreciated getting to work on this project with Kevin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Your life should consist of more than commuting, working, eating, surfing the Internet, sleeping and watching TV. Your life should be filled with purpose-driven experiences and projects that bring excitement, passion, energy, and authentic meaning and joy into your life.”
― Richie Norton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Chris</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/21/Pairing-with-Chris/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/21/Pairing-with-Chris/</id>
    <published>2015-07-20T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-02T23:46:19-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I was able to step back into my comfort zone as a designer. I worked with Chris on the same application that I was working on with Malcolm &amp;amp; Craig yesterday. I was excited to fix up some of the unstyled work that I saw yesterday that needed some love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our team stand-up Chris showed me a page that he had worked on the day before. He had already put together some great styles that we could carry into the forms, lists, buttons, etc for our current page. He also showed me the grid that he had made and was testing out based off of the BEM (Block, Element, Modifier) naming convention. Since CSS can quickly become a spaghetti mess with hot glue instead of spaghetti sauce, the designers at 8th Light and conscientious designers everywhere are constantly testing and looking to create maintainable CSS with limited dependencies. It was cool to see how Chris was trying to make improvements to his code by carrying these conventions into his grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, today we felt the pain of environmental issues which cut into our work time a great deal. This is just something that one has to except on a big project with many developers, and conflicting requests. This is something that my mentor has constantly reminded me of - things may not go as smoothly as your optimistic selves may think things will go. As a consultant you have to account for things going terribly wrong or you’re going to find yourself scrambling to meet an unrealistic deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our developers on the team kindly helped us move past the environment &amp;amp; project road blockers. Sadly, now Chris’s auto-reloader which was speeding up his workflow was unsupported so we had to find a workaround to bring it back. Once we got through the set-up, Chris and I were able to implement our design changes and brainstorm some design improvements to 8th Light’s SCNA conference website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with different designers, I have found that each one has their own workflow preferences. For example, some prefer to develop in the browser as where others preferred making several changes in their editors and then seeing them all at once. A similarity that I have seen… VIM. Although, Microsoft visual studio did not allow for VIM Chris found a plug-in that him and the developers were able to use to speed up their workflow. Things still weren’t perfect, but today I learned that that comes with each client project having a different environment. Craftsman have to be comfortable being uncomfortable and willing to work with what they are given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I'm continually trying to make choices that put me against my own comfort zone. As long as you're uncomfortable, it means you're growing.” – Ashton Kutcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Malcolm</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/20/Pairing-with-Malcolm/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/20/Pairing-with-Malcolm/</id>
    <published>2015-07-19T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-02T23:46:19-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Malcolm and Craig on an ASP.net project written in C#. I had never worked in those environments nor had I worked within Microsoft Visual Studio so it was like I was in a foreign country. However I did my best to follow along, help, and learn as much as I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the team’s daily stand up, Malcolm took some time to catch me up on the details of the project that we would be working on. He explained that we would be working on changing the structure of the way the backend was currently handling a process in order to better execute the end desired behavior. He took me through the white boarded diagram of the old system as well as the new system and explained how everything would work with our added changes. Because i’m a visual learner, this was a great way to put everything into context. And as he went through the diagram I couldn’t help but think about how disciplined craftsman must be to constantly bite the bullet and grow &amp;amp; change their software in order to reach the best possible solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the biggest take away that I got from working with Malcolm and Craig was seeing how a pair should work together in order to make progress and positive changes. Although they were pairing remotely they worked great together and seemed to have a nice workflow. They both took turns “driving” - writing code, while the other took the role as an active “passenger”. I say active because the passenger was always asking questions, adding input, and working toward a solution with the driver. They both stayed positive, included me, and made me laugh all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“…in my mind a craftsperson is someone who not only creates something from nothing from materials of their choice, but usually puts a part of themselves into what they make. A good craftsperson takes the time and effort to make something of quality which is worthwhile to have and which will still function way after the crafted item has been made. Good craftsmanship is synonymous with quality products.“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Eric</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/17/Pairing-with-Eric/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/17/Pairing-with-Eric/</id>
    <published>2015-07-16T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-02T23:46:19-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a long day yesterday it was nice to have a more relaxing day today. I treated myself to Starbucks Chai Tea Latte like I do most Fridays to reward myself for another good week. I had the first part of the day to set up my computer for the internal iOS app that Eric and I would be working on the second portion of the day. I installed the latest version of Xcode, pulled the repos i’d need for the project from Github and started to read documentation on that I thought might be helpful for building the app. I also used this time to work on a few business cards for the London Craftsman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a successful week 2 company stand up, Eric and Emmanuel explained the app that the group had been working on - an internal ping pong queue named “Slam”. They then showed me the features that they had already developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although they were eager to jump right into styling I couldn’t help but want to start from the beginning and sketch out a user flow to come up with some additional fun features. Having time to utilize the entire design process and meet tight deadlines is not something that I have been able to do during my apprenticeship so I really wanted to use it for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guys were very welcoming to the idea of mapping out a user flow so together we started from the beginning creating an enjoyable user-flow chart. We then began fleshing these ideas out more in the form of low fidelity wireframes using Balsamiq Mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started from the first step the user would take while using the app. This would of course be logging in. We decided that using google authorization would be a good option for 8th Lighters to login and tie themselves to an identity so we could add features such as ranks, stats, and leaderboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fun day, we made really good progress on the wireframes and began talks about possible branding ideas. I’m really excited to see this app grow and be used (hopefully soon!).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
