<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-07-16T22:53:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Eric</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/17/Pairing-with-Eric/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/17/Pairing-with-Eric/</id>
    <published>2015-07-16T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-25T18:19:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pairing Calendar" src="/images/Tour_calendar_day5.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a long day yesterday it was nice to have a more relaxing day today. I treated myself to Starbucks Chai Tea Latte like I do most Fridays to reward myself for another good week. I had the first part of the day to set up my computer for the internal iOS app that Eric and I would be working on the second portion of the day. I installed the latest version of Xcode, pulled the repos i’d need for the project from Github and started to read documentation on that I thought might be helpful for building the app. I also used this time to work on a few business cards for the London Craftsman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a successful week 2 company stand up, Eric and Emmanuel explained the app that the group had been working on - an internal ping pong queue named “Slam”. They then showed me the features that they had already developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although they were eager to jump right into styling I couldn’t help but want to start from the beginning and sketch out a user flow to come up with some additional fun features. Having time to utilize the entire design process and meet tight deadlines is not something that I have been able to do during my apprenticeship so I really wanted to use it for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guys were very welcoming to the idea of mapping out a user flow so together we started from the beginning creating an enjoyable user-flow chart. We then began fleshing these ideas out more in the form of low fidelity wireframes using Balsamiq Mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started from the first step the user would take while using the app. This would of course be logging in. We decided that using google authorization would be a good option for 8th Lighters to login and tie themselves to an identity so we could add features such as ranks, stats, and leaderboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fun day, we made really good progress on the wireframes and began talks about possible branding ideas. I’m really excited to see this app grow and be used (hopefully soon!).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Nelsol</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/16/Pairing-with-Nelsol/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/16/Pairing-with-Nelsol/</id>
    <published>2015-07-15T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-25T17:39:24-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pairing Calendar" src="/images/Tour_calendar_day4.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with my mentor, Nelsol. Through this experience I was able to truly get a feel of what a normal day for a designer at 8th Light might look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Nelsol and I were going to be joining the team I worked with yesterday for their iteration planning meeting and design session I caught Nelsol up on the new feature that the team was looking to add based on user input &amp;amp; data. The proposed feature was a search for the App (Global or specific has yet to be decided yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an extended IPM with a client we were eventually able to join the team for the meeting. Mike went through the data and charts with the client, pain points, assumptions we had, and what problems the search feature would solve for the users. An important statistic that he brought up was that the search function would solve an issue that the apps most active users were having - the app having trouble handling so much data at once. Ultimately and our hope being, more users would be utilizing the app in this way in the near feature. For that reason, tackling this problem would benefit our best users as well as our best future users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client was great, and even offered a few pain points that we hadn’t thought of. Once we added those to our list we began our design session where each participant, even the clients, were asked to create four drawings in 10 minutes with their ideas for how the search feature should be displayed and how it should function. Through these drawings and exercise we were able think creatively without boundaries and quickly come up with several solutions. We shared these solutions with each other and worked together toward narrowing down the best solution for the search feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the meeting, Nelsol and I worked together on a few client tickets. I was quickly thrown out of my comfort zone when Nelsol said that we would be using VIM as our text editor. I had meant to learn VIM during my apprenticeship but juggling all of my responsibilities pushed that further and further. Even though Nelsol had told me to start learning VIM in my spare time he was very patient with me as I slowly made changes and scrambled to remember each key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the painful pace at which i moved through the editor I was overwhelmed with the spaghetti code of the project and how the pages were laid out. I would be lying if I said working with this code base didn’t scar me with how many dependencies and redundant lines there were. Thinking positively - it makes me appreciate other projects i’ve worked on or have been able to start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Legacy code. The phrase strikes disgust in the hearts of programmers. It conjures images of slogging through a murky swamp of tangled undergrowth with leaches beneath and stinging flies above. It conjures odors of murk, slime, stagnancy, and offal. Although our first joy of programming may have been intense, the misery of dealing with legacy code is often sufficient to extinguish that flame.﻿”-― Michael C. Feathers, Working Effectively with Legacy Code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Mike</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/15/Pairing-with-Mike/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/15/Pairing-with-Mike/</id>
    <published>2015-07-14T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-25T16:57:05-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pairing Calendar" src="/images/Tour_calendar_day3.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Mike D on an iOS app project. I was excited to work with Mike because we’ve always had great conversations at lunch but I haven’t had the opportunity to work on his project during my apprenticeship. He also did a great job helping out with a group of visitors from Mobile Makers yesterday – all of the kids were entranced while he talked about his daily activities as one of our main iOS developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start things off Mike took me through the app and all of its current features. We worked through a couple of the support tickets and talked about some of the current user pain points that the team was looking to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to improve upon the app the team has been trying to let user input, data &amp;amp; stats drive their next steps and prioritize which pain points are the most urgent. In order to do this Mike and I began began collecting data &amp;amp; stats from our database. With the data we created charts to better represent the data to our client in our next iteration planning meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process excited me for a couple reasons. I think its great that the team is making an effort to solve user pain points using data driven design. Going this route will be much more effective than implementing a new feature based on pure assumption. The other thing that excited me was having a team of hardworking developers take part in the design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"What makes people passionate, pure and simple, is great experiences. If they have great experience with your product and they have great experiences with your service, they’re going to be passionate about your brand, they’re going to be committed to it. That’s how you build that kind of commitment." –- Jesse James Garrett&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Kyle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/14/Pairing-with-Kyle/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/14/Pairing-with-Kyle/</id>
    <published>2015-07-13T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-21T22:48:11-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pairing Calendar" src="/images/Tour_calendar_day2.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Kyle, 8th Light’s writer. Although we didn’t write a single line of code together I learned a lot about all of the hard work Kyle does behind the scenes to make 8th Light a special place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start off our day Kyle and I worked on reviewing and editing a blog post submission by another Craftsman. 8th Light encourages their employees to write and talk about their passions, technical, and non-technical topics. Sometimes its not always easy for people to express their thoughts into a cohesive blog or talk. That is where Kyle comes in to help everyone produce something they can feel proud of by making sure the flow of the piece makes sense and that grammatical errors are obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another project that Kyle has been working on is bringing back and improving company “Stand Up.” Stand Up is a time where everyone in the company comes together to talk about the projects that they are working on, and any successes or failures that they may have had. This helps everyone in the company stay informed about the company's progress and what their colleagues  have been working on. Last week Kyle did a great job putting together “Stand Up” and acting as MC. In order to keep on improving “Stand Up” Kyle and I went through the feedback form responses that he received and brainstormed some fun ideas with our VP of Sales &amp;amp; Marketing. After our meeting I worked on implementing a few graphs for the blog post about “Stand Up” that Kyle was going to send out to share the feedback results and Kyle multitasked on a few of the things on his list of things to do. I couldn’t help but get the feeling that Kyle does 100 things at once. Somehow he’s able to have a sense of humor through all of his tasks which is really refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the graphs I worked on creating today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="StandUp" src="/images/blog/StandUp_Stats_Q1.svg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="StandUp" src="/images/blog/StandUp_Stats_Q2.svg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="StandUp" src="/images/blog/StandUp_Stats_Q3.svg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="StandUp" src="/images/blog/StandUp_Stats_Q4.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="words-of-wisdom-from-the-day"&gt;Words of Wisdom from the day:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Knocked down and kicked out of all your pride”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But you're living with the thunder that you have inside”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You gotta open up your life”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;– JUICEBOXXX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing with Ginny</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/13/Pairing-with-Ginny/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/13/Pairing-with-Ginny/</id>
    <published>2015-07-12T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-14T22:32:37-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pairing Calendar" src="/images/Tour_calendar_day1.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my first day of pairing I paired with Ginny and the studio team - Mike E., Sylwia, and Diana who is our newest Craftswoman. We started out our day with our daily standup to discuss what each person worked on on Friday, if they had any “blockers”, what they were planning on working on that day, and what features were most urgent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After standup, Ginny, Slywia, Diana, and I started working on a priority feature for a client project that is launching very soon. We were creating a form which would process and supply the user with a code that they would need to then copy. In order to make the user-experience better we wanted to have the code automatically highlighted when it appeared. In order to do this the team used Javascript which they could place right into the html:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Sneakingrocky/c89c9d6fe5df543c6100.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working on that feature the team split off to complete the other stories. Ginny, Diana and I continued to work on making additions to the project and I was excited to be able to contribute to some of the more designer territory stories but also that I was able to follow along well with Ginny while she tackled some backend work.
After lunch we all had an IPM (iteration planning meeting) with our client who is getting ready to launch soon. It was awesome to see everyone in action, hear the questions from both the client and, the craftsman, and the way they all worked together to figure out what was needed to wrap up this project and pass it over to the client team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the meeting we all discussed a user experience issue and came up with a nice solution together. I helped Sylwia add some style additions and then continued to work with Ginny for the rest of the day. What I loved about pairing with Ginny was that she would say every step that she was doing which made it very easy to follow along and follow her thought process - this is hard to find! A lot of developers want to get from point A to point B as fast as possible with or without their pair still in the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great first day! The crazy and impressive thing about this team is that they were all versed in several client projects and had to balance time between each. And what I loved more than anything was the communication between them all on the state of the projects, the willingness of each person to help one another move a roadblock or solve a nasty bug. So while I originally thought that pairing meant that I would solely be working with one person - their great teamwork allowed me to work with every single person on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Teamwork is the ability to work together toward a common vision. The ability to direct individual accomplishments toward organizational objectives. It is the fuel that allows common people to attain uncommon results." –Andrew Carnegie”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Final Stretch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/07/12/The-Final-Stretch/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/07/12/The-Final-Stretch/</id>
    <published>2015-07-11T22:53:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-14T21:17:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve hit an important milestone of my Design Residency here at 8th Light. I am in my last month of my apprenticeship which means that I will spend the next month trying to show what i’ve learned in the last 5 months and prove that I have what it takes to earn a position as a Design Craftsperson here at 8th Light. It is also an opportunity for me to see what it is like to work with other Craftsman, explore some of our client projects, and to gauge whether it’s truly the right fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next two weeks I will go on a “Pairing Tour” which means that I will be pairing with a new person every day. I’m really excited to continue to work alongside others as my last month of client work with Emmanuel and Geoff has been such a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rolled an amazing group of people for my tour  and review board so I know it’ll be a fun couple of weeks and i’m no doubt going to learn a great deal from each person. I’ll use this fuel the energy I know i’ll need to complete two weeks of challenges following my tour and to prepare for my speech where I’ll most likely turn red thanks to my Irish side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="some-goals-i-have-for-my-tour"&gt;Some goals I have for my tour:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to get better sleep than I have during my apprenticeship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask tons of questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be a good pair who’s engaged in the work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay positive even if I feel out of my element&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blog about each day of my tour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id="my-schedule"&gt;My Schedule:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pairing Calendar" src="/images/Tour_calendar.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You have to fight to reach your dream. You have to sacrifice and work hard for it.
- Lionel Messi”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
